Whitney is a romance, drama, music film directed by Angela Bassett.
Chronicles Whitney Houston's rise to fame and turbulent
relationship with husband Bobby Brown.
Whitney Houston, played by Yaya DaCosta.
Bobby Brown, played by Arlen Escarpeta.
Robyn Crawford, played by Yolonda Ross.
Cissy Houston, played by Suzzanne Douglas.
Clive Davis, played by Mark Rolston.
Babyface, played by Wesley Jonathan.
Whitney is a 2015 American biographical film directed by Angela Bassett based on American singer Whitney Houston (Yaya DaCosta) and her
turbulent marriage to R&B artist Bobby Brown (Arlen Escarpeta) that premiered on Lifetime in North America on January 17, 2015.
Whitney received mixed-to-positive reviews from critics, with DaCosta's performance as Houston and Bassett's
direction being praised but Escarpeta's casting and the film's accuracy being criticized.
Bassett was nominated at the Directors Guild of America Award for Outstanding Directing – Miniseries or TV
Film and at the Black Reel Awards for Outstanding Director in a Television Miniseries or Movie.
The movie stars Yaya DaCosta as Houston, Arlen Escarpeta as Brown and Yolonda
Ross as Houston's longtime friend and road manager Robyn Crawford.
Whitney is set in a period of five years (1989–1994) when Houston was catapulted to worldwide
success due to her film debut The Bodyguard and its subsequent soundtrack.
Filming lasted 20 days, primarily occurring in Los
Angeles and Santa Clarita, California.
Canadian R&B singer Deborah Cox performs all of Houston's vocals in the film, including "I Will Always Love
You", "I'm Your Baby Tonight", "I'm Every Woman", "Jesus Loves Me" and "The Greatest Love of All".
Additionally, songwriting/production team The Jackie Boyz performed Brown's
vocals for "Every Little Step" in the Soul Train Awards scene.
The film explores themes of biography, rhythm and blues
(r&b), crack cocaine, biting, woman director.
The tone is emotional.